Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) Of Albany, New York Records
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) Of Albany, New York Records1863-1996
nam_apap137
Young Women's Christian Association (Albany, N.Y.)
20.21 cubic ft.
The collection documents the history of the YWCA of Albany, which was founded in 1888 by a group of women led by Mrs. Acors Rathbun in order to provide housing and recreational activities for young women searching for work. Through the years, the organization expanded to include classes, childcare, athletics, essay contests, teen issue programs, and an annual awards dinner honoring women. Strengths include the extensive photographic material and meeting minutes from the board of trustees and directors. The collection is weakest at the beginning and end of the YWCA of Albany's existence.
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Administrative History
In 1888, a group of women in Albany, New York, led by Mrs. Acors Rathbun, formed an organization that would provide inexpensive housing for the young women who were searching for work in the city. This was a national trend for many women coming from rural communities who were forced to look for work in bigger cities. This was during the time of the Industrial Revolution when many of the products produced at home, such as cloth, were being replaced by factory-made materials.
The solution of Rathbun and her committee members was to rent a house at 128 State Street and hire a matron to be in charge of the house. The committee members performed the housekeeping duties. Evening classes were offered to residents in embroidery, penmanship, English and bookkeeping. This marked the beginning of the Albany chapter of the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA). In 1891, a house at 5 Lodge Street was purchased for the organization's purpose, and in later years, houses at 2, 3, and 4 Lodge Street were also purchased. The Rathbun Memorial Gymnasium and pool were constructed to provide women with physical education classes as well. In 1926 the last private residence on Lodge Street was purchased for the YWCA. In 1964, a major renovation took place, creating two more floors of residential rooms, a new cafeteria and a lobby. ["History of the YWCA of Albany, New York", Series 1, Box 9, Folder 14].
In 1906 the Albany YWCA became a charter member of the national YWCA organization. Like the Albany YWCA, the national organization "literally began as a movement; its name [coming] later. The pulse of the movement was felt first in England in 1855, and then in the United States in 1858". [Jennifer Chiu, 1999. The Early Years. Washington, D.C.: YWCA of the U.S.A. http://www.ywca.org/html/B5b1.asp (19 February 2003). The first American YWCA was formed in New York City]. The organization in Boston, MA, formed in 1859, would be the first American organization to officially use the name YWCA in 1866. [Jennifer Chiu, 1999.The First Associations. Washington, D.C.: YWCA of the U.S.A. http://www.ywca.org/html/B5b3.asp (19 February 2003)].
The early years of the YWCA brought a number of services to the women of the region. A Glee Club was formed of State Normal College students in 1907. The Y House, a dormitory for women opened in 1918 for students of the State College for Teachers on South Lake Avenue. In 1926, the YWCA rented a building at 219 Ontario Street from the State College for Teachers for use as the Y House. [Geoffrey P. Williams, 2003. Chronological History of the University at Albany, SUNY. Albany: University at Albany Libraries. http://library.albany.edu/speccoll/chronology.htm (26 February 2003)].
The first half of the twentieth century brought a number of clubs and programs to the women of the region. The Industrial League brought together girls working in factories, homes, restaurants, and other service industries to offer programs in physical education, citizenship and social activities. The Girls Reserve, a program for junior and senior high school girls, emphasized community service and socializing. ["Albany, New York YWCA 1929-1930", Series 3, Box 1, Folder 5]. The Federated Business and Professional Club promoted citizenship, leadership and cultural education for professional women. ["Business and Professional Clubs, YWCA, 1941, Handbook", Series 3, Box 1, Folder 6]. The Thursday Afternoon, consisted of young married women who learned dressmaking, knitting, family care, and home decoration. The Club was also involved in war relief work during World War II. ["Scrapbook, Thursday Afternoon Club", Series 4, Box 3, Folder 1]. The Outing Club, formed in the 1950s, provided trips to New York City, hiking and skiing trips, picnics, bowling, square dancing, and horseback riding to men and women. ["Scrapbook, Outing Club", Series 4, Box 3, Folder 5].
In 1977, faced with financial pressures and deteriorating buildings, the Albany YWCA sold their Lodge Street facilities to the City and County of Albany. They moved to 28 Colvin Avenue and renovated the rented quarters in 1982 to provide an updated childcare space, exercise room, kitchen, and offices. In 1988, the YWCA bought the building and renovated the building yet again to meet the current standards and needs of the community.
In 1996, due to a drop in membership and financial troubles, the Albany chapter of the YWCA cancelled all but two programs, and let go 14 of its 17 staff members, transferring many of the programs to the Schenectady YWCA. In 1997, the Albany YWCA sold off its facility at 28 Colvin Avenue, thus closing its doors after 108 years of service to the community. ["Albany YWCA suffers from lack of fiscal fitness". (April 17, 1996) Times Union, p. A1].
The collection documents the activities of the Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) of Albany, NY, from its creation in 1888 to 1995. The organization was originally formed to provide reasonably priced housing for women and a number of professional and recreational activities. Through the years the organization expanded its operations to include clubs, day care programs, aerobics, karate, and ballet classes, essay contests, teen issue programs, and an annual awards dinner honoring women, both local and national.
The collection includes administrative files such as account reports, annual reports, bills of sale, program operating expenses, correspondence, grant applications, insurance policies, incident reports, membership ledger books, mortgages, deeds, bonds, and history of the YWCA papers. Also included in the collection are board of director meeting minutes and correspondence, board of director treasury reports, board of trustee meeting minutes and correspondence, executive committee meeting minutes, various other committee meeting minutes, brochures, programs, newsletters, news clippings, scrapbook material, photographs, negatives, slides (not extensive), videotapes, and posters. The memorabilia includes pins, ornaments, handkerchiefs, inscribed brass plates, banners, a seal imprinter, and a gavel.
The YWCA of the USA is documented in brief. This material consists of several posters, public service announcements, photographs, ornaments, pins, stickers and a history of the organization.
One strength of the collection is the extensive amount of photographic material, including a framed portrait of the founder of the Albany chapter. Other strengths are the board of director and trustee meeting minutes, from 1933 to 1995 and news clippings and scrapbooks from the 1910s to the mid 1990s. The news clippings and much of the scrapbook material were preservation photocopied.
The collection is weak at the beginning and end of the chapter's 108-year history. Correspondence is also limited in quantity. Some papers, such as programs and fliers glued into disintegrating scrapbooks, are extremely brittle. The earliest annual reports are hard bound and vary in condition. Record books and Annual Reports from the turn of the century are damaged. The covers and bindings are broken and pages are loose. They are extremely fragile.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Administrative Files, 1863-1996
Series 2: Board and Committee Files, 1930-1995
Series 3: Public Relations, Programs, and Events, 1911-1995
Series 4: News Clippings and Scrapbook Material, 1905-1995
Series 5: Photographs, 1911-1995
Series 6: Memorabilia, undated
.
Series arrangement statement: SUNY will complete.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the Schenectady YWCA in June 2002.
One photograph is available for viewing online from the University at Albany Libraries' Digital Collections database. See also the following related collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives: the Helen Quirini Papers (APAP-102) contain selected annual reports, committee minutes, correspondence, program schedules, speeches, and a history of the Schenectady YWCA; the Department of African and Afro-American Studies (UA-611) contains a subject file on the Black History Month Essay Contest of 1987; and the American Association of University Women, Albany Branch (APAP-002) has correspondence from 1988-1989.
In addition, the Pruyn Collection of Albany History at the Albany Public Library (Main branch) also contains Albany-YWCA materials.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
African Americans and Civil Rights Organizations; Women; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Neighborhood and Community Associations; Education; Athletics and Sports; Albany, New York; Africana Studies
Subject and Genre Headings
Young Women's Christian Association of the USA; Young Women's Christian Association of Albany--History; Young Women's Christian Association of Albany--Buildings; Women--Religious life--New York (State)--Albany; Women college students; Women--Education--New York (State)--Albany; Women--Housing--New York (State)--Albany; Women--Services for--New York (State)--Albany; Women--Societies and clubs--New York (State)--Albany; Women--New York (State)--Albany; Minutes; Scrapbooks; Photographs; Annual reports; Correspondence
Container List
- Administrative Files, 1863-1996; nam_apap137-1; 5.26 cubic ft.
  This series contains records dating from 1889 to 1996, with the exception of one bond agreement dating from 1863, prior to the creation of the YWCA of Albany, NY. It includes account reports, annual reports, bills of sale, program operating expenses, correspondence, grant applications, insurance policies, incident reports, membership ledger books, mortgages, deeds, bonds, and the history of the YWCA.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Accountant Report and Supplemental Report, 1944; 1957; nam_apap137-1_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accountant Reports, 1958-1960; nam_apap137-1_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Accountant Reports, 1961-1962; nam_apap137-1_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Accountant Reports, 1963-1968; nam_apap137-1_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Accountant Reports, 1969-1970; 1972-1976; nam_apap137-1_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Accountant Reports, 1977-1982; nam_apap137-1_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Accountant Reports and Correspondence, 1982-1991; nam_apap137-1_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Accountant Annual Reports, 1990; nam_apap137-1_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - After School Program, Annual Report, 1994; nam_apap137-1_9 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - After School Program, Claims to Albany County, 1993-1995; nam_apap137-1_10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - After School Program, Youth Bureau Contracts, Applications, Insurance Papers, 1993; nam_apap137-1_11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1915-1918; nam_apap137-1_12 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1920-1926; nam_apap137-1_13 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1930-1940; nam_apap137-1_14 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Annual Reports, 1940-1945; nam_apap137-1_15 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reports, 1945-1950; nam_apap137-1_16 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Annual Reports, 1950-1955; nam_apap137-1_17 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Annual Reports, 1958-1959; 1962-1966; nam_apap137-1_18 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Annual Reports, 1968; 1971-1990; nam_apap137-1_19 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, Non-YWCA, 1975-1978; nam_apap137-1_20 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Application for Funds from Housing and Development Act, 1974; nam_apap137-1_21 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Baby Sitting Certificates, Undated; nam_apap137-1_22 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Billing and Operations, Handwritten Notes, 1976; Undated; nam_apap137-1_23 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bills of Sale, 1939; nam_apap137-1_24 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Budget and Financial Ledger, 1980; nam_apap137-1_25 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Budget and Financial Ledger, 1980; nam_apap137-1_26 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Budget and Financial Ledger, 1981; nam_apap137-1_27 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Budget, 1991; nam_apap137-1_28 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Budget, 1992; nam_apap137-1_29 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Buildings and Grounds, 1989-1996; nam_apap137-1_30 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Building, 28 Colvin Street, Purchase and Renovation, 1986-1987; nam_apap137-1_31 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Building, Lodge Street Purchase, Sale, Correspondence, 1925; 1939; 1971-1977; nam_apap137-1_32 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cafeteria Operations Report, and Proposal Budget, 1963; nam_apap137-1_33 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Capital District Builder's of Educational Achievement, Annual Report, 1994; nam_apap137-1_34 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Capital District Builder's of Educational Achievement, Budget, 1994; nam_apap137-1_35 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Capital District Builder's of Educational Achievement Claim, 1994; nam_apap137-1_36 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Capital District Builder's of Educational Achievement, Compliance Reports, 1994-1995; nam_apap137-1_37 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Capital District Builder's of Educational Achievement, Correspondence, 1994; nam_apap137-1_38 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Capital District Builder's of Educational Achievement, Final Claim, 1993; nam_apap137-1_39 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Capital District Builder's of Educational Achievement, On-Site Monitoring by DFY (Division For Youth), 1994-1995; nam_apap137-1_40 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Capital District Builder's of Educational Achievement, Program Documentation, 1994; nam_apap137-1_41 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Capital District Builder's of Educational Achievement, Virginia Trip, 1994; nam_apap137-1_42 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Children's Center, Advancement of Funds, 1994; nam_apap137-1_43 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Children's Center Claim, 1994; nam_apap137-1_44 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Children's Center, Contracts, Lease Agreements, 1993-1994; nam_apap137-1_45 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Children's Center, Correspondence, 1994-1995; nam_apap137-1_46 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Children's Center, Expenditures, 1994; nam_apap137-1_47 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Children's Center, Head Start Family Worker Job Description and Project Request, 1995; nam_apap137-1_48 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Children's Center, Instructions on Filing a Claim, 1994-1995; nam_apap137-1_49 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Children's Center, Magazine Articles, Undated; nam_apap137-1_50 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Children's Center, New York State Bar Association Grant, 1993-1995; nam_apap137-1_51 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Children's Center, Policies and Procedures, 1994; nam_apap137-1_52 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Children's Center, Volunteer Services, 1994-1995; nam_apap137-1_53 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cleaning Service, Correspondence, 1991; Undated; nam_apap137-1_54 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Community Directory, 1959; 1963-1968; nam_apap137-1_55 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Contributions, 1991; nam_apap137-1_56 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Constitution and By-laws, Undated; nam_apap137-1_57 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Construction and Renovation, 1963; nam_apap137-1_58 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Corporate Resolutions and Correspondence, 1977-1993; nam_apap137-1_59 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Council of Community Services, Voucher, 1994; nam_apap137-1_60 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Day Camp Lawsuit, 1975-1977; nam_apap137-1_61 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Department of Labor, Forms and Correspondence, 1988; nam_apap137-1_62 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Employee Record, 1950; nam_apap137-1_63 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Financial Statement, Preliminary, 1987-1988; nam_apap137-1_64 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Financial Papers, Miscellaneous Income, Endowment Funds, 1956-1976; nam_apap137-1_65 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Grant Application, Correspondence, 1977; nam_apap137-1_66 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Grant Application, Women's Educational Equity Act, Undated; nam_apap137-1_67 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Grant Booklets and Brochures, 1977-1978; nam_apap137-1_68 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Grants, New York State Energy Office, 1991; nam_apap137-1_69 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - General Correspondence, 1986; Undated; nam_apap137-1_70 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Incident Reports and Safety Plan, 1971-1978; 1991; 1994; 1995; nam_apap137-1_71 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Income and Expenses Ledger, 1982; nam_apap137-1_72 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Income and Expenses Ledger, 1988; nam_apap137-1_73 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Insurance Correspondence, 1974-1975; nam_apap137-1_74 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Insurance Policy, 1938; nam_apap137-1_75 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Internal Revenue Service, Payroll Papers, 1990; nam_apap137-1_76 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Internship Paper, 1978; nam_apap137-1_77 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Investment and Finance Statements, 1959; 1967-1979; nam_apap137-1_78 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Investment Loan, 1990-1991; nam_apap137-1_79 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Investment Management Agreement, 1974; nam_apap137-1_80 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Legal Agreement, National Commercial Bank and Trust Company, 1974; nam_apap137-1_81 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Liberty Partnership Program, 1994; nam_apap137-1_82 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Mayor's Fund, 1993-1994; nam_apap137-1_83 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Membership Ledger, 1981; nam_apap137-1_84 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Membership Ledger, 1982; nam_apap137-1_85 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Membership Ledger, 1983; nam_apap137-1_86 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Membership Ledger, 1984; nam_apap137-1_87 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Membership Ledger, 1988; nam_apap137-1_88 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Membership Policies and Procedures, 1977; nam_apap137-1_89 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Membership Reports, 1980-1993; nam_apap137-1_90 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Mortgage Applications, 1987; nam_apap137-1_91 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Norstar Bank, Correspondence, 1990-1991; nam_apap137-1_92 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Payment Requests, Day Care Services, 1976; nam_apap137-1_93 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Personnel Action Report, 1991; nam_apap137-1_94 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Personnel Policies and Procedures, Undated; nam_apap137-1_95 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Personnel Recommendations, 1958-1959; nam_apap137-1_96 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Program Cost Information, 1974; nam_apap137-1_97 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Program Description and Purpose Statement, Undated; nam_apap137-1_98 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Publicity Report, 1954; nam_apap137-1_99 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Receipt Book, 1980; nam_apap137-1_100 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Records Retention Schedule, Undated; nam_apap137-1_101 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Re-incorporation Act, 1942; nam_apap137-1_102 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Report of the Architectural and Engineering Service by B.M. Cadman Associates, 1958; nam_apap137-1_103 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Reports to National YWCA, 1977-1978; nam_apap137-1_104 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Report of Study, 1958; nam_apap137-1_105 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Sheppard, James, Public Accountant, Correspondence, 1989-1993; nam_apap137-1_106 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - South Africa, Anti-Apartheid Correspondence and Papers, 1985-1989; nam_apap137-1_107 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Study Report on Albany YWCA, 1971; nam_apap137-1_108 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Summer Camp Scholarship, 1989-1992; nam_apap137-1_109 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Swimming Department, Monthly Report, 1959-1960; nam_apap137-1_110 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Swimming Pool Rental, College of Saint Rose, 1989; nam_apap137-1_111 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Swimming Pool Rental, YMCA, 1990-1992; nam_apap137-1_112 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Tax Exemption Papers, 1989-1990; nam_apap137-1_113 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Teen Choices, Albany Community Service Project, 1994; nam_apap137-1_114 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Teen Choices, Audit, 1994-1995; nam_apap137-1_115 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Teen Choices, Budget and Amendments, 1994; nam_apap137-1_116 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Teen Choices, Claims, 1993-1994; nam_apap137-1_117 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Teen Choices, Contracts and Agreements, 1988-1993; nam_apap137-1_118 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Teen Choices, Correspondence and Payment Lists, 1993-1994; nam_apap137-1_119 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Teen Choices, Final Claim, 1994; nam_apap137-1_120 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - United Way, Budget and Funding Applications, 1994; nam_apap137-1_121 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - United Way, Correspondence and Program Survey, 1994; nam_apap137-1_122 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - United Way, Program Allocations, 1993; nam_apap137-1_123 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Workmen's Compensation, 1979-1990; nam_apap137-1_124 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - YWCA of Albany Building Fund, Report, 1960; nam_apap137-1_125 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - YWCA Calendar of Special Projects, 1960; nam_apap137-1_126 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - YWCA Contracts, Undated; nam_apap137-1_127 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - YWCA History, National and Local, Undated; nam_apap137-1_128 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - YWCA Retirement Fund Report and Papers, 1977; 1993; nam_apap137-1_129 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Annual Financial Report, 1932-1935; nam_apap137-1_130 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1889-1896; nam_apap137-1_131 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1898-1908; nam_apap137-1_132 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1899-1909; nam_apap137-1_133 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1909-1918; nam_apap137-1_134 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports, 1918-1928; nam_apap137-1_135 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1919-1928; nam_apap137-1_136 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1928-1939; nam_apap137-1_137 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Annual Reports, 1939-1948; nam_apap137-1_138 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Board of Managers Meeting Minutes, 1897-1902; nam_apap137-1_139 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Board Minutes, 1903-1911; nam_apap137-1_140 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Board Minutes, 1921-1931; nam_apap137-1_141 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1888; nam_apap137-1_142 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Membership Dues, 1903-1908; nam_apap137-1_143 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Membership Lists, 1891-1942; nam_apap137-1_144 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Membership Lists, Undated; nam_apap137-1_145 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Expenses Account Ledger, 1925-1928; nam_apap137-1_146 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Expenses Account Ledger, 1967-1969; nam_apap137-1_147 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Membership List, 1905-1906; nam_apap137-1_148 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Payroll Ledger, 1927-1930; nam_apap137-1_149 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bank Account Ledger, 1963; nam_apap137-1_150 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Membership Cashbook, 1890-1903; nam_apap137-1_151 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Visitors Book, 1888-1905; nam_apap137-1_152 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Affidavit of Title, 1913; nam_apap137-1_153 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
  - Assignment of Mortgage, 1916-1921; nam_apap137-1_154 (Box 1A, Folder 2)
  - Attendance Lists, Y-Wives, 1974; nam_apap137-1_155 (Box 1A, Folder 3)
  - Balance Sheets, Undated; nam_apap137-1_156 (Box 1A, Folder 4)
  - Bonds, 1911-1925; nam_apap137-1_157 (Box 1A, Folder 5)
  - Budgets, Salary Earnings, Sales Numbers, 1979; nam_apap137-1_158 (Box 1A, Folder 6)
  - Deeds, 1870-1921; nam_apap137-1_159 (Box 1A, Folder 7)
  - Endowment Fund, 1970; nam_apap137-1_160 (Box 1A, Folder 8)
  - Instructor Lists, 1991; nam_apap137-1_161 (Box 1A, Folder 9)
  - Legal Agreements, 1902-1922; nam_apap137-1_162 (Box 1A, Folder 10)
  - Mortgages, 1903-1917; nam_apap137-1_163 (Box 1A, Folder 11)